Take your food quietly.
Thank you.
Oh, thank you.
I'm sorry about this.
I'm being pursued for being
critical of the government.
Really.
But I have allies
all across Japan.
Oh, I see.
When this world becomes ours,
what we're doing will be right.
So rest easy, masseur.
I will make this a good
world, I'm sure of it.
I'm called Tsuru.
I'm Ichi.
Eighty and five...
Eighty and six...
Eighty and seven...
Eighty and eight...
ZATOICHI
What could have happened, really?
Something that strange shouldn't happen.
Welcome home.
Is there someone here?
Good of you to come, Ichi!
Hey, come on in, you've
come just in time.
I was going to eat it by myself,
but it tastes better with company.
Oh, thank goodness.
Come in, come in, the wind is so strong.
Well, I thought you
might not show up, sir.
I had waited there the whole time.
Sit over here.
It's been a while since I heard the
sound of the waves, it's refreshing.
The official said, "A
blind man can't be a thief."
So I asked, "Who decided that?"
He responded, "I did!"
I got ticked off, so I took his jutte.
Then he screamed "Thief!"
And chased after me.
I was confined for three days,
and given one hundred lashes.
Well, if you get hit that many times,
at least your shoulders won't get stiff.
Yeah, the stiffness in my shoulders
is all gone now, I feel refreshed.
If you stay in a cell for too long,
then it kind of turns into your home.
Except the lock.
The difference between your own
house and a jail cell is the lock.
In your house, the lock is on
the inside, and you secure it.
A jail cell is locked
from the outside, right?
If you can lock it,
then it's not a jail.
If it's locked from the other
side, then you are in the cell.
In that case, I'm glad that
your house doesn't have a lock!
Not locking the door
is part of how I am.
Oh, Mr. Ichi, stand up a moment.
Now now, turn that way, turn that way.
There you go.
I made this to give it to you.
What do you think?
Is this silk?
That's right.
The measurements are just right.
Oh yeah, there's one more
thing I need to give you.
But this is such a nice kimono...
Do you remember this money?
You left it here some time ago, I kept
it aside so I could give it to you.
I left that money for
you, so you could use it.
You left it for me?
Yeah, that's yours.
Oh, I see, then thank you.
So is it really mine?
That's right.
All right.
In that case, I will
give it to you again.
Now, take it.
Today is a good day
for payouts at the Tenjin house.
Use that as collateral, and
be sure to make some money!
See if it's odd or even,
go and try it out!
Thank you very much!
What are you doing, hurry up!
Young men nowadays are...
Thank you for coming all this way.
He's still young, so I'm thinking
of teaching him the business.
This was used by the government
during the chaos caused by Amakusa.
It's an antique.
Antique guns are one thing, but
men don't become more valuable overtime.
A man just gets older.
But you let that old
Torazou control you...
...I can tell where
you'll be in the future.
You take control.
For today's celebration,
I brought twenty guns.
Boss, the other guests besides
Boss Torazou have arrived.
Hail Lotus Sutra, Hail Lotus Sutra...
Chou!
One and one, Han!
One coin.
I lost.
Mr. Ichi!
Mr. Tsuru!
Are you starting the
revolution in here?
I feel like I've gone blind.
Having eyes where there
aren't any, that's gambling.
This is not an influential era...
...like before, when we forcibly
gained control from the populace.
The truth of the matter is, if we
took away everything they've got...
...it would ruin our lives also.
We have to think about the future.
From here on, we have to work
together, and be friendly.
Goemon is still young, but
please treat him as an equal.
I used to change his
diapers when he was little.
Greet them!
The people who live in this business of
ours eventually have to spill red blood.
Work together and be
friendly with everyone?
You're joking!
Treat each other as equals?
Well, that's fine.
If there are people who are my
equal, then I will treat them as such.
Hey, wise one.
How dare you talk to
your elder that way?
He's not my elder, or anything.
You bastard!
Don't underestimate us!
Now, now, let him say what he wants to.
Make it quick!
You killed a lot of people, and made a
lot of people cry when you were young...
...in order to widen your territory.
Am I right?
How I kill someone, how I make
someone cry, that's all my choice.
I have problems dealing
with antiques, you know?
So, gentlemen, I will take care
of your business from here on.
If any of you have a problem
with that, bring it on.
Oh, Tenjin!
Man, that felt good.
Nice speech.
Well, I'm the only one
here who's your equal.
How did it go?
Did you take care of it?
Well, go and take a look.
As long as you continue being
the local authority, Mr. Hasshuu...
...I'll help you out, no matter what.
As long as I continue to
be the local authority, eh?
Are you a fool?
Do you think I'm going to hand
this position over to anyone else?
I'm going to send bad people to hell,
and I will walk the path to heaven.
I'm going higher than heaven!
How about it, want to come with me?
You said you would help me
out, but what kind of help?
Excuse me.
Ohan of the Bosatsu Family is here.
Hello.
Miss Bosatsu, what took you so long?
I apologize for being late.
Well, Master, it's been a long time.
How's everything?
Fine, thankfully.
Oh, that's good to hear.
Thank you very much.
Why don't you sit here,
I'm leaving anyway.
Hey!
Get the tray for the boss
of the Bosatsu family.
And bring up three warmed bottles.
Hasshuu is here.
Yes, sir.
Right away.
Hasshuu?
As in the local authority?
It seems like it.
Why would Mr. Hasshuu
come to a place like this?
If he stops by at a gambling
hall, he'll make good money.
I'm sorry we're so late.
Oh, no.
Where is the Younger?
Well, he is upstairs,
with Mr. Hasshuu...
Has there been any trouble?
What?
Oh, no, not at all.
This is my thanks.
Oh, thank you, you're
always thinking of us.
What can I say to repay you?
If there is anything I can do
with my body to satisfy you?
Thank you.
Excuse us!
Please...
Excuse me.
The dice are going in.
Ready.
Bosatsu, if only you could
have gotten here sooner.
I'm sorry.
We have received a generous gift
from the head of the Bosatsu family.
You are the only person
I lower my head to.
Hasshuu is waiting.
Four and six, even number!
I am Ohan, nice to meet you.
I am...
Lord Hasshuu.
Bosatsu...
Hey, hey!
I'm going to raise a
drink with this one!
I will make you one of my followers.
What do you think?
Our world has become
a good one, hasn't it?
For a government official to
be able to drink with a gambler.
That's it, that's what's so amusing!
If you become one of my followers...
I, Ohan of the Bosatsu, cannot
become one of your followers.
I am sorry.
Chou.
Chou!
Is there any player betting on Han?
No Han?
No one's betting on Han?
What's going on?
All of the players do what
that fat blind man says.
Everyone is betting the
same one, there's no contest.
This game is a draw.
I'm going to roll the dice.
Please make your bet.
Everyone, make your bet!
Now!
Make your bet!
Han!
All right, is there
anyone betting on Chou?
Anyone for Chou?
Are there any players for Chou?
Bring a box.
House bets with a box.
Here we go!
Four and three, Han!
Fool!
If this keeps up, this won't pass
for gambling or anything else!
But as long as our
customers are happy...
Please let me roll the dice once.
You want to roll the dice, do you?
Well, my eyes aren't so good,
but I'd like to try anyway.
This is the cup.
And the dice are here.
Okay, I've got it.
What's this?
The dice of the Goemon family have
the character "five" instead of dots.
As you can see I am blind, please
forgive me for my clumsiness.
Come on, let's do this!
Mr. Ichi!
All right, go ahead.
Thank you.
Chou!
Is anyone dropping out?
They are all accounted for.
Here we go!
Four and six, Chou!
By the way, everyone, I don't
have a marker, but I have money.
Would someone bet
against my sixteen ryo?
All right, I'll take it!
I'll take it!
Okay, then, let's split it then.
Half each, right.
Let me bet, too.
Move!
This is big!
I'm betting for Han!
This will be the next throw.
Has everyone bet?
Yes, everyone has.
Is there anyone dropping out?
It doesn't look like
anyone is dropping out.
If no one is dropping
out, then here we go!
Go!
Five and one.
That's Chou, so I win.
And that's enough for
me, thank you very much.
You're in luck!
Thank you, I'll be going now.
Thank you so much.
Show us those dice!
You just swapped them, didn't you?
Here are the dice.
You were cheating, weren't you?
Cheating?
Don't joke.
Your dice have a "five" character
and these don't, so they are mine.
Well, excuse me.
Hey, come here.
Come here, here!
Feed him to the fish!
Bastard!
Your boss's character comes through
when his underlings act like this.
What did you say?
Please stop.
You guys certainly have been
saying some strange things.
I was watching earlier, but...
...isn't the rule to bet with
your marker on the dice in the cup?
Isn't it?
This isn't an amateur's place, after all.
You bet on the dice that
landed outside the cup.
I have never seen nor heard of such
a stupid gambling parlor as this.
Right, Younger?
If the customers here are
treated in such a manner...
...we won't be able to see our
business through to fruition, correct?
Hey!
Fools!
Sir, we are so sorry.
There are so many guys who
have no idea what they're doing.
Well, thank you.
Give him a lantern.
I'm going to become a
man that's untouchable...
...even Hasshuu can't
tell me what to do.
Here you are, a lantern.
A lantern for a blind man?
Please take your time.
We've made preparations.
It's a dark night tonight.
Thank you for your kindness.
Hey, you!
That's as far as you go.
It's one step from the River Styx.
And they said that it was a dark night.
What about it?
Try and get me already!
There's someone else there, right?
You're Zatoichi, correct?
My father has told me a lot about you.
Oh, you're the head of the Bosatsu.
You helped me out at the gambling
hall, and this is how it ended up.
They're the ones who drew first.
I've never entered the
bath with a man before.
But why would you,
someone who dislikes men...
Ah, this man cannot see, after all.
But you can see what I look
like in your mind, right?
I see her...
Who do you see?
My mother.
How old was she?
Twenty-eight.
Then she's the same age as me.
The same as you, Boss?
Call me Ohan.
Boss...
Sorry, I mean, Ohan.
You've let me see
such a wonderful thing...
This must be what they mean by paradise.
I lost my vision when I was two...
...so the last time I saw her,
she was still twenty-eight.
That's why, no matter
how much time passes...
...in my mind's eye, she never ages.
Now, she's younger than I am now.
If she were alive, I
might make her my wife.
It's hard...
I wonder if this is what they mean
by not wanting to leave someone.
I love you.
The speech you gave at
the attack of the Iioka...
Do you remember that?
We of the Yakuza...
...are gamblers who walk
the forbidden back-streets.
The ones most hated in the
whole world, so to speak...
No matter what happens...
We have to see our
business through to fruition...
Even a woman like me will
put her life on the line...
...and see her
business... through to fruition.
Yes!
Yes...
And you'd be happy just
sinking into the water...
For you to live in a place like this...
Don't fool with me!
What is it?
You said something like
"don't fool with me" just now...
Did I say that?
It must be my stomach grumbling.
It is rumbling.
What is?
Your stomach.
No thanks, I'm a warrior,
I don't take handouts.
This is for your stomach, not you.
I'm grateful.
This is delicious!
It's got beans in it.
Let me paint you.
Huh?
A picture.
Act normal.
Just normal, don't do anything.
Try holding your cane
in front of your face.
A little further away...
That's good.
Don't move!
Hey, what are you doing?
Move!
You're in the way, move!
Man, there are so many different colors.
Is there red?
Yes, there are many kinds of red.
Do you like red?
Yes.
What kind of color is it?
Huh?
It's like the evening sun...
...or a woman's lips.
I was wondering...
...if you could tell me
which way the tavern is.
This is a very high-up place, isn't it?
Yes, the view is wonderful!
And the wind feels so nice!
The dumplings are good for you.
Because you could use them as eyeballs.
Miss, let me have some dumplings.
Mr. Ichi!
I'm so happy, I didn't think
we'd meet again so soon.
Mr. Ichi, ever since we parted
ways, I'd been thinking about it.
I wanted to pay you back somehow...
Then I met these masseurs.
I thought that I could be their guide!
Mr. Tsuru, that makes me very happy.
We're heading up to the Kasamori
Kannon to pray in the morning sun next.
Everyone, this is my
best friend, Mr. Ichi.
Nice to meet you, I am Matsunoichi.
I am Takenoichi.
I am Umenoichi.
I am Suginoichi.
I am Kuroichi.
I am Harunoichi.
Mr. Ichi, how would you
like to come along with us?
There's no need to hold back,
even though we're not acquainted.
How about coming along with us?
Thank you, but I have
something I must take care of.
Perhaps next time.
Well, if you'll excuse me.
Farewell, take care.
Thank you very much.
Here is your food.
Oh, here it is!
Well, that certainly made my day.
Mr. Ichi, here.
This is spiritual water from Mt. Kiyosu.
They say it's good
for washing one's eyes.
Here, take it.
Mr. Ichi, the next time we
meet, you better greet me first!
Are you the one who
wants to be the bodyguard?
Any letters of recommendation?
We have a policy of not employing
samurai who don't have recommendations.
Where were you before you came here?
I don't talk about where I've been.
Look at my face and decide.
I'm expensive.
Expensive?
I am an instructor of the Onoha
Single Blade Style, Sukezaemon Kuroma.
I challenge you.
Come.
Draw your blade!
Go ahead.
Mr. Kuroma...
Thank you for all of your hard
work, what an embarrassment!
Thank you for the meal.
Thank you very much, please come again!
Burdock root, please.
Yes, sir!
Here you are.
Come on in!
Thank you forthe meal.
Thank you very much!
Give me two bottles of sake.
Okay, two bottles of sake!
I got it.
Come on in, are you staying the night?
Yes.
You're lucky, we have a nice room.
Thank you.
Ah, come on in!
Come in!
Bring me the check!
Yes, sir!
All right, Jongara time!
Jongara, jongara, jongara, jongara!
Jongara, jongara, jongara...
I don't care if I die!
Bring it out!
Now everyone, please come here!
Now, I'm going to
sing the Jongara Bushi!
So please listen well!
The shamisen is great!
The neck is even better!
Ah, when I was a
child, my young heart...
The song I learned when my
mother carried me on her back...
That's the Tsugaru Jongara Bushi!
That's it...
That's red.
Red?
Yeah.
This is red...
Right!
That is the red you like so much.
This is red?
Well, you've done well to find it out.
I think that this is red.
All right, let's have a drink!
Hey, drink up.
Come on, why are you holding back?
No, I...
This is my room, so
I'm not holding back.
That's why I'm telling
you to start drinking.
Now, drink up.
All right, let's play
Scissor-paper-rock?
The one who loses has to drink.
The one who loses...
Paper-scissors-rock!
Oh, I lost.
I lost.
Paper-scissors...
Paper-scissors-stone!
Man, I lost again.
Paper-scissors...
Wait, wait.
Paper-scissors-stone!
I won!
Damn it, I lost...
Well, I have no choice...
I lost after all, I have no choice.
The liquor you are forced
to drink tastes even better...
Man, this has kick.
Are you happy, not being able to see?
That's the first time
anyone has asked me that.
Do you have any problems
being able to see?
Pretending not to see
something, I guess.
I cannot see, but have
to live as if I could see.
Your problem is pretty extravagant.
Do you look into mirrors?
Yeah.
I've always wondered if my
face was being shown in it...
This is a memento of my mother.
She always used it.
She used to tell me someday
I would see my face in this mirror.
Do you want to see it?
Can you see it?
Sir, the red has become much deeper...
Sleepy Ichi, Ichi of Tenma...
What the, you're already asleep?
Yes.
Your eyes are closed all
day, how can you sleep?
Aren't you going to sleep?
No.
I'll rest well when I'm dead.
Are you leaving?
Yes.
Thank you for taking care of me.
My bill, please.
A samurai paid it for you earlier.
Are you all right?
Yes.
Please come again.
Hey bird!
Hey, hey!
Mother Bird!
You left your baby here...
Left, left, left, left, left!
Don't go right, it's dangerous!
Left, left!
Left!
We told you to go on the left side!
Big Sister!
We're home, Big Sister!
Our guest fell into a hole.
The egg is going to hatch.
Hello.
Nice to meet you.
I happened to meet the children of
this house, and came to say hello...
Please come inside.
Please!
Please, please!
I'm so hungry.
Hurry, let's eat.
My tummy is empty.
Shall I help you?
All right, everyone, let's eat.
Join us, Mr. Ichi.
Thank you.
Thank you forthe food!
Let's eat!
It's hatching!
It's hatching?
Is it hatching?
It's hatching.
What's written on it?
Hmm?
A leaf is falling...
A falling leaf...
"A falling leaf does not hate the wind."
"A falling leaf does not hate the wind"?
Huh, I understand...
But what is that?
It's written on your bamboo pipe.
Huh?
A falling leaf does not hate the wind.
It's that gentleman.
But the falling leaf does hate the wind.
Please make it nice and clean.
Understand?
Nice and clean!
Just a little more.